American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIb. 1807-1825 APS.Archives.IIb APS.Archives.IIb
American Philosophical Society
American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIb
1807-1825
APS.Archives.IIb
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the American Philosophical Society Archives. For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
American Philosophical Society.
- Papers
  - DATES
    - An Account of experiments made on palladium, found in combination with pure gold, June 23, [1809]; 10x8; Cloud, Joseph, ca. 1770-1845
      Scope and Contents note
      [read] D.S. 4p. and end. Printed: A.P.S. Trans., VI, 407-411.
    - W[illiam] Rawle to ----, February 23, [1811]; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Rawle, William, 1759-1836
      [Philadelphia] 1 p. A.L.S. Approves proposed alterations in the classes of the [American Philosophical] Society.
    - George Gibbs to J[ohn] Vaughan, March 5, [1811]; 7 3/16" x 8 15/16"; Gibbs, George, 1776-1833
      Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of diploma of membership in the American Philosophical Society.
    - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Jan. 20, [1813]; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Barton, William, 1754-1817
      A.L.S. 1p. (see Ms. comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 1, no. 48) Asks favor.
    - Persons elected members of the Am[erica]n Philos[ophical] Soc[iet]y since Jan[uar]y,1813, [Philadelphia], ----, , [1814]; 7 3/4" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
      1 p. D. Mentions T.Jefferson in a note. FILM 199 FRAME 361
    - Report relative to the formation of a historical branch of the society, made by P.S. DuPonceau, , [1815]; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
      D. 1p. and end.
    - Will[ia]m Meade to [Caspar] Wistar, April 4, [1816]; 7 7/8" x 10"; Meade, William
      Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: his work On the origin and progress of galvanism...
    - Tables of contents for volumes of correspondence copied from the James Logan correspondence at Stenton, [1819?]; 13-1/4x8; Logan, Deborah Norris, 1761-1839
      D. 17p.and end: 10p.are in hand of John Vaughan. (NOTE: These tables of contents refer to the original 4 volumes presented by Mrs Logan to the Society. Vols.I and II are now bound in Vol.I.)
    - Suggested prospectus for a publication of the James Logan correspondence, copied by Mrs. Deborah Norris Logan, [1820]; 9-3/4x8; American Philosophical Society. Historical and literary committee
      D. 6p., end. by P. S. DuPonceau.
    - Letter to [Johann Severin] Vater, March 18, [1821]; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
      Resumé of A.L. 1p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 2, p.41.) Sends list of books forwarded to him.
    - Letter to [Johann Abraham] Albers, March 18, [1821]; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
      Resumé of A.L. 1p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 2, p.41.) Asked that he procure a certain book.
    - Letter to Willemot, Nov., [1822]; 7-1/2x5; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
      L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning the Abbe Haüy's intended gift to the APS. For answer to this letter, see D.B. Warden to J.Vaughan; Nov. 6, 1823.
    - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Dec. 6, [1822]; 8x5; Collins, Zaccheus, 1764-1831
      A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publication.from L.D.Schweinitz.
    - Letter to ---- ----, [1825]; 8" x 14 1/2"; Cairu, José da Silva Lisboa, Visconde de, 1756-1835
      [Rio de Janeiro] L.S. 2p. and end. In Spanish. Received his diploma of membership in the American philosophical society from Condy Raguet. Appreciation for honor. Presents his Constituicao moral. Cf. Minutes - May 19, 1826.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, January 1, 1807; 7" x 9"; Stockler, Francisco de Borja Garçaõ
    Lisbon, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Acknowledges election to membership in the Philosophical society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 2, 1807; 13x8; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    A.L. 4p. Contains copy of letter from McKean to [B.Vaughan]; Aug. 22, 1806 and remarks by Prof. Cleaveland concerning a solar eclipse.
  - Jona[than] Williams to Thomas Jefferson, January 2, 1807; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Williams, Jonathan, 1750-1815
    [Philadelphia], 1p. A.L.S. Informs Mr. Jefferson of his reelection as president of the American Philosophical Society. FILM 199, FRAME 207
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams and C.W. Peale, Jan. 12, 1807; 8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, pres. U.S., 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges re-election as president of the A.P.S. Printed: Bergh, v.11,133 Bur. of rolls, v.6,505-S.1,v.12,59
  - Jane Aitken to (John) Vaughan, January 17, 1807; 4" x 6 5/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests $2.50 be given bearer (William Blair) for the purchase of two pairs of stockings. FILM 199 FRAME 174
  - Jona[than] Williams to John Vaughan, January 17, 1807; 7 7/16" x 9"; Williams, Jonathan, 1750-1815
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents listed books to the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the University of Pennsylvania, Jan. 20, 1807; 14-1/2x9-1/2; Högelmüller, Georg, ritter von
    Vienna, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In French. Asks for aid in his enterprise. For enc., see: Broadsides. Högelmüller. Proposition faite aux amis des sciences... Enc.originally in letter from Clymer to APS; July 25,1807
  - W[illia]m Goforth to Thomas Jefferson, January 23, 1807; 8" x 9 7/8"; Goforth, William
    President of A.P.S., Cincinnati, 5pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Details concerning bones of the mammoth. Enclosed in: Th[omas] Jefferson to [Caspar] Wistar, February 25, 1807. FILM 199 FRAME 121
  - Jane Aitken to (John) Vaughan, January 31, 1807; 3 3/4" x 5 5/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests $10. be given bearer "on Account of the Printing the Transactions."
  - Asiatic Society of Calcutta to the Secretary of the A.P.S., February 5, 1807; 7 3/4" x 10"; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S.: W[illia]m Hunter, Secretary. Presents to the A.P.S.: Asiatic Society, Transactions, IX.
  - Account of a skeleton head (Monax) presented to the President of the American Philosophical Society by John Stewart of Greenbriar County, February 5, 1807; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Wistar, Caspar, 1761-1818
    Virginia. [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. Com. FILM 199 FRAME354
  - Royal Academy of Sciences of Lisbon to Tho[mas] C. James, February 6, 1807; 7 7/8" x 9 13/16"; Academia Real das Sciencias de Lisboa
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Lisbon, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S.: Cypriano Ribeiro Freire. Presents to the A.P.S., a collection of the principal writers of the history of Portugal.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, February 16, 1807; 6 1/4" x 7 7/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    1 p., address and endorsement, A.N.S. Requests $20. be given the bearer "on Acct. of Thomas Cooper Esqr."
  - Freestone quarries on the Potomac and Rappahannoc rivers., February 19, 1807; 7 1/4" x 9"; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    ----, 13 pp. and endorsement. A.Com.S. (Incomplete.) Printed in A.P.S. Transactions. o.s., VI, 283-293.
  - Th[omas] Jefferson to [Caspar] Wistar, February 25, 1807; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, pres. U.S., 1743-1826
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses letter from Dr. [William] Goforth on bones of the mammoth. Will instruct Captain [William] Clark to investigate Big Bone Lick. Printed: Bergh, V.11,158 Microfilmed - Film 199,92
  - Report of committee on A.Fothergill's paper on population, March 6, 1807; 6-1/2x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Saml. F. Conover and Joseph Cloud. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.395.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, March 10, 1807; 6 1/2" x 8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    (Philadelphia), 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests $10. be given bearer (Charles Cooper) "on account of printing the Transactions."
  - Report of committee on [Benjamin Henry] Latrobe's report on building stone, March 20, 1807; 5x7; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: C.W. Peale and Adam Seybert. 1p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p.395. Printed: Trans. ,o.s.,vol.VI, 283 ff.
  - Report of committee on Varlé' s canal locks, March 20, 1807; 1-1/2x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    [read] D.S.: C.W.Peale and Thos. T. Hewson. 1p.and add. (see Ms.Comm. to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 32a.) Cf. Minutes, p.395. For additional correspondence, see: Letter from Latrobe to C.W. Peale; March 4, 1807: and, Letter from A.P.S. Report...; [read] March 20, 1807. Varlé to Wister; Nov. 20, 1806.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], March 20, 1807; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Caire-Morand, Antoine, b. 1747
    read, A.L.S. 3p. and end. In French. Enc. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Natural history, vol. 1, no.38.) Concerning his work on precious stones. Mentions B.Franklin. For enclosure (?) see Caire-Morand: Recherches sur ll'asterie. FILM 199 FRAME 383 FILM 54-64 FRAME 240
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, March 20, 1807; 10x8; Foronda, Valentín, 1751-1821
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 11p.and end. In Spanish. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Philology, literature, etc., vol. 1, no. 28.) Concerning the English and Spanish languages. Cf. Minutes, p.396.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 23, 1807; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Natural history, vol. 1, no.34.) Mentions T. Jefferson.
  - Th[omas] Jefferson to John Vaughan, March 24, 1807; 8 1/8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, pres. U.S., 1743-1826
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns Mr. Carey's letter concerning the donation of a Sanskrit grammar. Presents two volumes on the raising of sheep, particularly merinos. Microfilmed - Film 199,93
  - Cleland Kinloch to John Vaughan, March 26, 1807; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Kinloch, Cleland
    Weehaw, [S. C.], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates shells taken from high hills of the Santee river region. See Minutes, May 15, 1807, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 397.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, April 4, 1807; 4 3/4" x 8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    (Philadelphia), 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests $10. be given the bearer "on account of printing the Transactions."
  - Henry Muhlenberg to John Vaughan, April 9, 1807; 7 3/4" x 8 1/4"; Muhlenberg, Henry, 1753-1815
    Lancaster, 1 p.,address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will forward a calendar of the flora of Lancaster to A.P.S. Wishes to see Michaux. Botanical matters.
  - D. B. Warden to the Secretary of the [American] Philosophical Society, April 16, 1807; 4 3/8" x 7 1/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to A.P.S.: J. J. Combes-Dounous, Dissertations de Maxime de Tyr, 2v. and Cuvier's Eulogium on Priestley. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 399.
  - Report of committee on cold weather in Maine, April 17, 1807; 6x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Sam[ue]l B. Wylie and Thos.T.Hewson. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.396.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, April 24, 1807; 5 1/4" x 8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests $10. be given the bearer "on account of the Transactions printing."
  - F. R. Hassler to T[homas] C. James, Secretary of the A.P.S., April 30, 1807; 7 13/16" x 9 3/4"; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - W[illia]m Maclure to the [American Philosophical] Society, May 7, 1807; 8" x 9 3/4"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: a number of minerals collected in Europe; sixty-four volumes of the Journal de Physique and a subscription to the same. Signature reproduced in APS Proceedings, v. 91, no.3, page 240.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, May 8, 1807; 6 5/8" x 8 1/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests $20. be given Charles Cooper for the purchase of summer clothing.
  - Geo[rge] Izard to Thomas C. James, May 10, 1807; 7 3/4" x 10"; Izard, George, 1777-1828
    Bucks Co[unty], Pennsylv[ani]a, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Report of committee on the paper by Caire-Morand, May 15, 1807; 6-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Adam Seybert, M.Dickerson and Jn. Vaughan. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.397.
  - Report of committee on J[osé] J[oaquin] de Ferrer's paper on the eclipse of the sun, May 15, 1807; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Joseph Clay and R. Patterson. 1p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p.397.
  - D. B. Warden to the Secretary of the [American] Philosophical Society, May 20, 1807; 7 3/4" x 12 1/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S. four volumes in the name of Charles Philibert de Lasteyrie who desires to be elected a corresponding member.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, May 22, 1807; 5" x 7 7/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. Requests $10. be given the bearer on account of printing the Transactions.
  - Talbot Hamilton to John Vaughan, May 22, 1807; 7 1/4" x 9 1/4"; Hamilton, Talbot
    Church Alley, [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: [Johann Heinrich] Alsted, Encyclopaedia, 2v., formerly the property of [Benjamin] Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME 125
  - Sam[uel] Blodget to the President of the A.P.S., May 25, 1807; 7 1/4" x 7 7/8"; Blodget, Samuel, 1724-1807
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S. a copy of his Economica: a statistical manual of the U.S. FILM 199 FRAME 355
  - T[albot] Hamilton to John Vaughan, May 25, 1807; 7 3/8" x 9 3/8"; Hamilton, Talbot
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents cast iron medallion of Benjamin Franklin to A.P.S. See Minutes, June 17 1807, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 397. FILM54-61 FRAME 126
  - Letter to Tho[mas] C. James, secretary of A.P.S., June 3, 1807; 7" x 9 1/4"; Stockler, Francisco de Borja Garçaõ
    Lisbon, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership which was damaged in quarantine.
  - Extract from the minutes, July 7, 1807; 10x8; University of Pennsylvania. Trustees
    D.S.: Edward Fox. 1p.and end. Concerning philosophical inquiries to be made by Högelmüller. Enclosed originally in letter from Clymer to APS; July 23, 1807.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 10, 1807; 8" x 10"; Freire, Cypriano Ribeiro, chev. De
    Lisbon, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Relative to publications transmitted by order of the Royal academy of sciences. Mr. Stockler's membership in the APS.
  - Levett Harris to the Corresponding Secretary of the A.P.S., July 15, 1807; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Levett
    St. Petersburg, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S. from the Imperial Academy of Sciences of St. Petersburg, Transactions, XV.
  - Report of committee on Benj[amin] Shultz' paper on light, July 17, 1807; 6-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: C.Wistar, jr.and Jno.R. Smith. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.398.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 25, 1807; 10x8; Clymer, George, 1739-1813
    Philadelphia, L.S.: Geo.Clymer and A.J.Dallas. 1p.and add.:Jno. Vaughan, end. Enc. Concerning aid for Högelmüller from the University of Pennsylvania. For enc.see: Broadsides.Högelmüller Proposition faite aus amis...: Högelmüller to U.of P.; Jan.20,1807: and U.of P.Trustee Extracts...; July 7, 1807.
  - W[illiam] Vaughan to John Vaughan, July 25, 1807; 8" x 10"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Is forwarding designated journals to the A.P.S.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, July 29, 1807; 4 1/2" x 7 3/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    1 p. address and endorsement. A.N.S. Request $20. for purchase of clothing and for school wages.
  - Rob[er]t H. Rose to John Vaughan, August 21, 1807; 8" x 10"; Rose, Robert H. (Robert Hutchinson), 1776-1842
    ----, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates specimens of Pennsylvania coal to the A.P.S. See Minutes, August 21, 1807, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 399.
  - W[illiam] Vaughan to John Vaughan, August 25, 1807; 7 13/16" x 12 1/2"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Is forwarding designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Eliza Ann.
  - J(ane) Aitken to John Vaughan, September 5, 1807; 5" x 8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests loan of $5.00.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Sept. 6, 1807; 4x7; Tatham, William, 1752-1819
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Will deliver his paper on longevity to Dr. Mease. Cf. Minutes, pp.401-402, for paper.
  - Report of committee on the paper by John Garnett for the Magellanic premium, Sept. 16, 1807; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R. Patterson, Thos.T.Hewson and Jno. R.Smith. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.399.
  - Sam[uel] Brown to B[enjamin] S[mith] Barton, September 20, 1807; 8 1/4" x 10"; Brown, Samuel, 1749-1828
    New Orleans, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates silver ores and other minerals from mines near Mexico City. See Minutes, November 6, 1807, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 401.
  - William Schultz to the American Philosophical Society, September 23, 1807; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Schultz, William
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Submits plan and description of a fire escape for the Magellanic premium. Plan and description missing. See Pro. XXII, pt. 3, 400.
  - Jane Aitken to (John) Vaughan, October 1, 1807; 3 7/8" x 8 1/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests $20. for purchase of winter clothing.
  - P. Pedersen to John Vaughan, October 16, 1807; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: Catteau-Calleville. Tabeleau des états denois, 3v. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 400.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, October 20, 1807; 4 3/8" x 5 7/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests loan of $50. for ten days "for purchasing the remainder of my wood."
  - Jane Aitken to (John) Vaughan, October 20, 1807; 2 1/4" x 4 1/2"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests $20. for clothing and schooling.
  - Report of committee on [Silvain] Godon's paper on observations to serve for a mineralogical map of Maryland, Nov. 20, 1807; 6-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: B.S.Barton, Adam Seybert, and M. Dickerson. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.401. Printed: Trans.,o.s.,vol.VI, 319 ff. For paper, see: Godon. Observations...; [read] Nov.6, 1807.
  - Report of committee on communication by William Tatham on longevity, Nov. 28, 1807; 5-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: C.W.Peale, N.Chapman and Zaccheus Collins. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.401.
  - Letter to the secretary of the American philosophical society, Dec. 3, 1807; 8" x 10"; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, L. 1p. and end. Acknowledges certain volumes presented by the APS.
  - Letter to [Messrs. Mease, Seybert and Dickerson], Jan. 9, 1808; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, pres. U.S., 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Acknowledges re-election as president of the A.P.S. Printed: Bergh, v.11,419. Bur. of rolls, v.6,321-S.1,v.12,355. FILM 199 FRAME 175
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to John Vaughan, January 27, 1808; 5 1/16" x 8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Treasurer of the A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S., in the name of Benjamin Dearborn of Boston, a ballot box and two pamphlets.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the paper of Mr. Ross Cuthbert, suggesting a new theory of the tides, February 5, 1808; 7 11/16" x 12"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Jno. R. Smith, Zaccheus Collins. Publication not recommended.
  - B[enjamin] Silliman to John Vaughan, February 8, 1808; 7 7/8" x 10 1/16"; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864
    Yale College, [New Haven], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. "We have concluded to communicate our memoir on the meteor to the [American] Philosophical society... " See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 404-405.
  - Benjamin Silliman and James L. Kingsley to John Vaughan, February 18, 1808; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Yale College, 4 pp. Transmits account of meteor of December 14, 1807.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the paper of Dr. Shattuck on the White Hills of New Hampshire, February 19, 1808; 7 3/4" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsements. D.S.: C[aspar] Wistar, Jr., James Woodhouse. Publication not recommended, as the author has been anticipated by Dr. Belknap.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred an instrument for the purpose of finding the longitude, February 23, 1808; 8" x 12 9/16"; American Philosophical Society
    invented by Mr. Timothy Kirk, [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson and three others. Report ordered to lie on the table. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 404.
  - L. Spalding to the Secretary of the A.P.S., March 1, 1808; 7 7/8" x 9 9/16"; Spalding, Lyman, 1775-1821
    Portsmouth, [N.H.] 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S., a copy of the Portsmouth bill of mortality for 1806 and 1807.
  - D. B. Warden to [Thomas C.] James, March 1, 1808; 6 1/8" x 8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Corresponding Secretary of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S. books listed herein.
  - Jane Aitken to (John) Vaughan, March 12, 1808; 4" x 6 3/4"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests loan of $20. "for paying the mens wages."
  - T[albot] Hamilton to Jno. Vaughan, March 15, 1808; 8 3/8" x 10 1/8"; Hamilton, Talbot
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: [David] Gregory, Elements of... astronomy, 2 vols. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 405.
  - Report of committee on [Benjamin] Silliman's and [James Luce] Kingsley's paper on a meteor, March 18, 1808; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.Hare, Jr. and Joseph Cloud. 2p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p.405. Printed: Trans.,o.s.,vol.VI, 323 ff.
  - Letter to the Philosophical society of Philadelphia, March (?) 18, 1808; 7 1/2" x 9"; Lasteyrie, C. de (Charles), 1759-1849
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Acknowledges election to membership about which he learned from M. Mease. Presents his work on the culture of cotton.
  - Talbot Hamilton to Jno. Vaughan, March 29, 1808; 7 1/2" x 9 3/8"; Hamilton, Talbot
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates four pigments found on the Lehigh to A.P.S. See Minutes, April 1, 1808, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 405.
  - W[illia]m Maclure to the [American] Philosophical Society, March 29, 1808; 8 3/8" x 12 1/4"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Jumilla, Spain, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends box of specimens of rock to the A.P.S., "which did not come to hand."
  - Jane Aitken to (John) Vaughan, March 30, 1808; 4 1/2" x 7 1/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Requests that $20. be given to Charles Cooper for schooling and the purchase of clothing.
  - Report of committee on [William] Thorn-ton's memoir on yellow fever, April 1, 1808; 6-1/2x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: C.Wistar, jr. and Thos.T. Hewson. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.405.
  - Letter to Tho[mas] C. James, secretary of A.P.S., April 2, 1808; 7 1/2" x 9"; Lasteyrie, C. de (Charles), 1759-1849